Early in the morning in June 2024, photographer Lee McGrath captured electric blue shimmering in the waves of Dunraven Bay, Wales.
2024年6月的一个清晨，摄影师李·麦格拉思在威尔士邓雷文湾的海浪中捕捉到了电蓝色的微光。
Lighting up the water was bioluminescent plankton.
照亮水面的正是生物发光的浮游生物。
Bioluminescence is the ability of certain organisms to produce light.
生物发光是指某些生物体能够生光。
It's a biochemical wonder involving a reaction between certain chemicals that create light without heat.
这是一种生物化学奇迹，涉及某些化学物质之间的反应，能在不产生热量的情况下发光。
Plankton, as seen in Wales, are tiny marine drifters, carried by ocean tides and currents.
正如在威尔士所见，浮游生物是微小的海洋漂流者，随潮汐和洋流移动。
And they're not the only creatures in the ocean with this illuminating characteristic – an amazing 76% of animals in our seas are bioluminescent, according to National Geographic.
它们并不是海洋中唯一具有这种发光特性的生物——根据《国家地理》的数据，海洋中高达76%的动物都是生物发光的。
It happens for a variety of reasons.
发光的原因多种多样。
For example, the deep-sea anglerfish has a glowing fin that sticks out of its head to attract prey, and jellyfish can emit light to attract mates.
例如，深海琵琶鱼有一个从头部伸出的发光鳍来吸引猎物，而水母可以发光来吸引配偶。
Similarly, the six-inch lantern shark, one of the world's smallest sharks, has light-up organs used for camouflage.
同样，六英寸长的灯笼鲨（世界上最小的鲨鱼之一）拥有用于伪装的发光器官。
But it's not just ocean life that can glow in the dark.
但并非只有海洋生物才能在黑暗中发光。
On land, fireflies dance with glowing abdomens as part of courtship rituals, while some fungi, such as the honey mushroom, contribute an eerie glow in forests, and are known as 'ghost mushrooms' in some cultures.
在陆地上，萤火虫舞动着发光的腹部，这是它们求偶仪式的一部分；而一些真菌，如蜜环菌，会在森林中散发出诡异的光芒，在某些文化中被称为"鬼蘑菇"。
In New Zealand, there is a freshwater snail which emits a glowing slime, and glow-worm caves attract hundreds of thousands of tourists a year.
在新西兰，有一种淡水蜗牛能分泌发光的黏液，而萤火虫洞每年吸引着数十万游客。
Scientists are discovering more and more glowing nature each year, says Linda Reinhold, an Australian scientist, but there's still a lot we don't know.
澳大利亚科学家琳达·莱因霍尔德表示，科学家每年都会发现越来越多的自然中的发光现象，但仍有许多未知。
She says it's easiest to see bioluminescent nature on land by using a UV torch, so next time you head out at night, pack one!
她说，在陆地上，使用紫外线手电筒最容易看到生物发光的自然现象，所以下次晚上出门时，带上一个吧！
You never know what you'll find.
你永远不知道会发现什么。